<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- RevolutionDCM/LoR -->
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by lcollins (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text Cities -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PEDIA_CATEGORY_CONCEPT_FOREVER</Tag>
		<English>4-Ever Concepts</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_ECONOMY_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Economic System Rework</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_ECONOMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Economic System Rework[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Having a treasury was useless in BTS, unless you were scamming the AI, who seemed to think it had a use. Research spending was too important, most of the time you never invested in culture, or wealth, or even espionage, because being on the cutting edge is too important. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Making Gold Useful[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A large part of why gold was useless was the fact that anything you could spend it on cost so much that it wasn't worth accumulating any gold. To change this, the cost to hurry production has been reworked, all civics can now hurry production with gold, and the cost to upgrade a unit has been reworked. The hurry production cost is now linear based on remaining hammers, and is mostly standardized across units and buildings, exceptions being settlers, workers, and wonders. The upgrade cost has been made linear as well. Hurrying a production with no actual production done yet costs 50 percent more. Overall the hurry production cost and unit upgrade cost is more reasonable now.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Dethroning the Technology Spending Slider[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The fact that gold can actually be spent reasonably help with encouraging a more dynamic range of civic spending throughout the game, but what really drives it home are the other four game options that have been added, two of which help players get tech from other players, one of which makes culture spending more useful, and the last makes spy missions more useable. The AI has also been adjusted to play with a much more dynamic economy.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]A Well Balance Economy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Now that you have more incentive to adjust your spending away from 100 percent research, adjusting your spending by 10 percent increments would be clunky, which is why the adjustment system has been modified. The outer set of buttons adjusts spending by 10 and the inner set by 1.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_TRAITS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Trait Rebalance</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_TRAITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Trait Rebalance[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Financial[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]It turns out, giving all of your cities a bonus to commerce yield is just way too good, because it not only increases your wealth spending, but also your technology, culture, and espionage spending, it was like if your spending sliders added up to 130 percent. It was for that reason that in nearly every game, leaders with financial walked all over those without it, and so the old financial trait is gone (Colossus got nerfed too). Financial now provides a 20 percent bonus to wealth generation as well as doubling the production speed of market.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Charismatic[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Not nearly as strong as financial was, but pretty clearly the second best trait in the game, this trait simply did too many good things, and so it no longer gives -25 percent XP needed for unit promotions.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spiritual[\BOLD] [PARAGRAPH:1]Mathematically, the lack of anarchy was simply not strong enough to compete with other traits. Spiritual has been given the XP cost deduction that Charismatic had, as well as also doubling the production speed of Cathedrals (and temples still)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_FORTS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Improved Forts</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_FORTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Improved Forts[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Introduction to Forts[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts in BTS (and Civilization4-Ever) provide a number of utilities that you may or may not be aware of, so let's recap quickly. Forts provide a defensive bonus to units standing on them, forts can base aircraft, forts count as cities for healing units, forts adjacent to the sea act as ports when determining if two points on the map are connected for trade, a fort (or two) can be used as a canal for naval units, and lastly forts will grant access to any resource (but not modify plot yields). Ok now that that's out of the way here are the changes that have been made to forts in Civilization 4-Ever.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Imperialistic Uses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts can now be built outside of your boarders. This is useful because forts now provide a single culture point per turn in each tile adjacent to them, which means they can be used to gather resources from outside your empire. Forts can be flipped to a foreign culture simply by being garrisoned by a unit from that culture. To slow the advancement of forts claiming resources across the globe, the construction of a fort now consumes a single worker. The AI has been taught that it can build forts in neutral territory, and has been encouraged to gather resources with them, as well as use them as staging facilities for attacks. The culture growth of a fort, or even a wall or forts, is far too small to ever threaten a city. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bombardments and Bombing Runs[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts can now be bombarded by siege weapons and aircraft in the same manner as cities, and also regenerate their defensive bonus over time, just as cities do. Aircraft will no longer be able to destroy the fort improvement unless it is at 0 percent defensive bonus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_GENERALS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Great Generals</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_GENERALS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Great Generals[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Great Generals now have another use, in addition to their old ones. Great Generals can now lead armies by remaining on the battlefield as a unit. If a unit is in range of a General, and that General has command points left, that General will provide bonuses to the unit, and in return will receive a trickle of XP. Here's how it works:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Command Radius (CR):[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This is how far away a unit can be from the General and still be able to receive benefits from their presence. A fresh General will have a command radius of zero, meaning that they will have to be on the stack with the unit they are leading.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Command Points (CP):[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Command Points are used up when a General assists in a combat, offensive or defensive, one per conflict. Command Points refill to maximum at the beginning of each of [BOLD]your[\BOLD] turns, keep that in mind if you plan on using them defensively.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Applying Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]If one of your units is engaged in a combat, that unit is within the command radius of a General, and said General has at least one command point, the General will automatically aid that unit in combat.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Promotions:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Morale: +Strength[PARAGRAPH:1]Tactics: +Withdrawal Chance[PARAGRAPH:1]Initiative: +First Strike Chances[PARAGRAPH:1]Operations: +CR +CP[PARAGRAPH:1]Woodland Training: +Forest/Jungle Attack[PARAGRAPH:1]Highland Training: +Hill Attack[PARAGRAPH:1]Shelter: -Collateral damage taken</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_SPIES_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Spies</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_SPIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Spies[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies no long start with commando, and have had their movement speed reduced, but they now gain XP from doing espionage missions, which can naturally be spent on promotions. Each turn a spy sits on a plot it reduces the cost of an espionage mission on said plot, to a limit of course.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Promotions:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Alchemist: Bonus to poison missions[PARAGRAPH:1]Deception: Less likely to get caught[PARAGRAPH:1]Escape Artist: Less likely to die if foiled[PARAGRAPH:1]Improvise: Decrease mission cost without fortifying[PARAGRAPH:1]Instigator: Bonus to unrest missions[PARAGRAPH:1]Logistics: Bonus to sight and movement[PARAGRAPH:1]Security: Bonus to counter-espionage</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_NAVAL_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Naval Combat</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_NAVAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Naval Combat[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Naval combat was a bit bland in BTS, and so a few changes have been made to make it more interesting.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Destroyers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Destroyers were the catch all utility boat in BTS, they simply did too much. Historically destroy were the weakest of medium sized ships as far as ship to ship combat went, but they were prized for their speed and their ability to hunt submarines. In Civilization 4-Ever their bombard has been weakened, their strength lowered (except against subs), their ability to combat air has been taken away, and their cost has been reduced. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cruisers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Cruisers are a new unit. They are able to intercept aircraft, and have a moderate bombard attack. They have the strength of the old destroyers, as well as the price, but cannot detect submarines.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Capital Ships[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Historically speaking, capital ships were in a class of their own when it comes to naval warfare, and due to their size, not many were built. The cost of battleships has been increased. The cost of carriers has also increased slightly.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Attack Submarines[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Attack Subs no longer get a bonus against other subs.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_OPTIONS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>New Game Options</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_OPTIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]New Game Options[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tech Trading[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Tech trading is now off by default. Historically it makes little sense, and the other game options act as sort of a replacement, but this option can be used if desired.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spies Return to Nearest City[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The name says it all on this one, spies will return to your nearest city instead of your capital with this option on. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Advanced Tech Bleed[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unbenounced to the player, a technology in BTS was actually cheaper if more civilizations already had it. This system's math was coarse and bland however. This new system takes into account knowledge of civilizations with the technology, open boarder agreements, defensive pacts, alliances, vassalages, and wars. If this option is turned off the old system will be used. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Technology from Pillaging[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This option encourages players to pillage more, as well as rounding out the new economy a bit (as it provides tech without spending). With this option on each time you pillage an opponent's improvements you will be given a few beakers in a random technology that they posses that you do not. The reward for capturing a city is much larger. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improved Culture Warfare[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]After reviewing the formulas used it can be easily determined that taking over territory with culture in BTS is not really possible / doesn't work like it should. This option completely reworks the way cities generate culture. With this option on cultural warfare is much more viable. If this option is turned off the old system will be used. This option is on by default. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Non-Lethal Combat[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In BTS combat is done by taking several turns, during each one of the two sides makes an attack on the other. This option makes it so that combat ends after a certain number of rounds even if both participants are still alive. The goal here is makeing doomstack vs doomstack feel less random. now you can look at how it went after a round of combat and decide to retreat or hold out for reinforcements without taking massive casualities. To balance this healing is disabled while an enemy is adjacent, and promotions do not heal. If this option is disabled the original fight to the death mechanic is used, healing can be done next to opponents, and promotions heal. This option is on by default.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MISC_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Misc Changes</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MISC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Miscellaneous Changes[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Implemented BUG (Beyond the sword Unaltered Gameplay) interface mods. [PARAGRAPH:2]Astronomy now requires paper, which prolongs the time between ocean exploration and ocean colonization.[PARAGRAPH:2]Forges now allow for an additional engineer, making it easier to plant a city in barren environments or on small islands.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Colossus now only affects the city that it is built in.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Great Lighthouse now only provides one trade route per costal city.[PARAGRAPH:2]All government civics can now hurry production with gold. This is part of the economic rework.[PARAGRAPH:2]Universal Suffrage now provides +1 Culture per Specialist in addition to its other effects, because hurrying with gold is no longer unique.[PARAGRAPH:2]Cities with enemies adjacent to them cannot hurry production. This is for balance but can be justified with the fact that cities are not usually self sufficient on the inside.[PARAGRAPH:2]Walls were too good at stopping early game aggression, and castles were lackluster, and so their resistances to bombardment have been swapped.[PARAGRAPH:2]Upgrading units now removes half of the unit's current hit points. This change is partially to balance out the gold decrease of upgrades, and partially to prevent armies from instantly becoming better when a new technology is reached. It's also logically justifiable as troops must be trained with the new equipment.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aircraft now gain minimal experience points from doing bombing missions. Bombers had no way good way of gaining XP before this. [PARAGRAPH:2]Slavery's cost to hurry production has been reworked.[PARAGRAPH:2]Culture output of Wonders has been halved. Industrial was too strong at cutlure pushing. This change was also made for the Improved Culture Warfare, and if you play with that option off you won't even notice this culture missing. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unbenounced to the player, advancing through the eras actually applies a penalty to your research and your economy in general. This penalty was linear in BTS. I have doubled the penalty for entering the medieval era and removed the penalty for entering the Renaissance. This change is both historically logical, and encourages more medieval wars, as the era is slightly longer.[PARAGRAPH:2]Espionage can now be built from cities, just like wealth, once computers have been researched.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will no longer spend Espionage points on players it considers friends or insignificant.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will only use spies to harass players that it is annoyed with, at war with, or considers a threat to winning.[PARAGRAPH:2]Removed the feature where building's double their culture output after '1000' turns (it was like 22 turns for some reason)[PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced Great Artist culture production to 8 from 12 and Great Work culture to 1200 from 4000[PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced SDI's chance to intercept nukes to 50% from 75% (nukes were really bad past lasers and for something that takes so many hamemrs to build it should never be that bad)[PARAGRAPH:2]Sistine Chapel Culture per specialist reduced to 1 from 2 and cupture per religious building reduced to 3 from 5. [PARAGRAPH:2]Took one scientist away from the library and gave it to the university. [PARAGRAPH:2]Roads/Railroads can now be destroyed with aircraft if there are no improvments on their tile. [PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced culture per resource of all corperations. [PARAGRAPH:2]Implemented Hi-Res Blue Marble Textures. </English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
