<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- RevolutionDCM/LoR -->
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by lcollins (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text Cities -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_FOREVER_VERSION</Tag>
		<English>Civilization 4-Ever v3.3.3</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_FOREVER_VERSION_SAVE</Tag>
		<English>4-Ever v3.3.3</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_HURRY_EMBARGO</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]City under siege[COLOR_REVERT]</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_UPGRADE_DAMAGE</Tag>
		<English>[COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]Reduces current strength by half[COLOR_REVERT]</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_PEDIA_CATEGORY_CONCEPT_FOREVER</Tag>
		<English>4-Ever Concepts</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_ECONOMY_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Economic System Rework</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_ECONOMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Economic System Rework[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Having a treasury was useless in BTS, unless you were scamming the AI, who seemed to think it had a use. Research spending was too important, most of the time you never invested in culture, or wealth, or even espionage, because being on the cutting edge is too important. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Making Gold Useful[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A large part of why gold was useless was the fact that anything you could spend it on cost so much that it wasn't worth accumulating any gold. To change this, the cost to hurry production has been reworked, all civics can now hurry production with gold, and the cost to upgrade a unit has been reworked. The hurry production cost is now linear based on remaining hammers, and is mostly standardized across units and buildings, exceptions being settlers, workers, and wonders. The upgrade cost has been made linear as well. Hurrying a production with no actual production done yet costs 50 percent more. Overall the hurry production cost and unit upgrade cost is more reasonable now.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Dethroning the Technology Spending Slider[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The fact that gold can actually be spent reasonably help with encouraging a more dynamic range of civic spending throughout the game, but what really drives it home are the other four game options that have been added, two of which help players get tech from other players, one of which makes culture spending more useful, and the last makes spy missions more useable. The AI has also been adjusted to play with a much more dynamic economy.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]A Well Balance Economy[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Now that you have more incentive to adjust your spending away from 100 percent research, adjusting your spending by 10 percent increments would be clunky, which is why the adjustment system has been modified. The outer set of buttons adjusts spending by 10 and the inner set by 1.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_TRAITS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Trait Rebalance</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_TRAITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Trait Rebalance[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Financial[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]It turns out, giving all of your cities a bonus to commerce yield is just way too good, because it not only increases your wealth spending, but also your technology, culture, and espionage spending, it was like if your spending sliders added up to 130 percent. It was for that reason that in nearly every game, leaders with financial walked all over those without it, and so the old financial trait is gone (Colossus got nerfed too). Financial now provides a 20 percent bonus to wealth generation as well as doubling the production speed of market.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Charismatic[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Not nearly as strong as financial was, but pretty clearly the second best trait in the game, this trait simply did too many good things, and so it no longer gives -25 percent XP needed for unit promotions.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spiritual[\BOLD] [PARAGRAPH:1]Mathematically, the lack of anarchy was simply not strong enough to compete with other traits. Spiritual has been given the XP cost deduction that Charismatic had, as well as also doubling the production speed of Cathedrals (and temples still)</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_FORTS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Improved Forts</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_FORTS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Improved Forts[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Introduction to Forts[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts in BTS (and Civilization4-Ever) provide a number of utilities that you may or may not be aware of, so let's recap quickly. Forts provide a defensive bonus to units standing on them, forts can base aircraft, forts count as cities for healing units, forts adjacent to the sea act as ports when determining if two points on the map are connected for trade, a fort (or two) can be used as a canal for naval units, and lastly forts will grant access to any resource (but not modify plot yields). Ok now that that's out of the way here are the changes that have been made to forts in Civilization 4-Ever.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Imperialistic Uses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts can now be built outside of your boarders. This is useful because forts now provide a single culture point per turn in each tile adjacent to them, which means they can be used to gather resources from outside your empire. Forts can be flipped to a foreign culture simply by being garrisoned by a unit from that culture. To slow the advancement of forts claiming resources across the globe, the construction of a fort now consumes a single worker. The AI has been taught that it can build forts in neutral territory, and has been encouraged to gather resources with them, as well as use them as staging facilities for attacks. The culture growth of a fort, or even a wall or forts, is far too small to ever threaten a city. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bombardments and Bombing Runs[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Forts can now be bombarded by siege weapons and aircraft in the same manner as cities, and also regenerate their defensive bonus over time, just as cities do. Aircraft will no longer be able to destroy the fort improvement unless it is at 0 percent defensive bonus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_GENERALS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Great Generals</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_GENERALS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Great Generals[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Great Generals now have another use, in addition to their old ones. Great Generals can now lead armies by remaining on the battlefield as a unit. If a unit is in range of a General, and that General has command points left, that General will provide bonuses to the unit, and in return will receive a trickle of XP. Here's how it works:[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Command Radius (CR):[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This is how far away a unit can be from the General and still be able to receive benefits from their presence. A fresh General will have a command radius of zero, meaning that they will have to be on the stack with the unit they are leading.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Command Points (CP):[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Command Points are used up when a General assists in a combat, offensive or defensive, one per conflict. Command Points refill to maximum at the beginning of each of [BOLD]your[\BOLD] turns, keep that in mind if you plan on using them defensively.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Applying Bonuses[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]If one of your units is engaged in a combat, that unit is within the command radius of a General, and said General has at least one command point, the General will automatically aid that unit in combat.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Promotions:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Morale: +Strength[PARAGRAPH:1]Tactics: +Withdrawal Chance[PARAGRAPH:1]Initiative: +First Strike Chances[PARAGRAPH:1]Operations: +CR +CP[PARAGRAPH:1]Woodland Training: +Forest/Jungle Attack[PARAGRAPH:1]Highland Training: +Hill Attack[PARAGRAPH:1]Shelter: -Collateral damage taken</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_SPIES_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Spies</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_SPIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Spies[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Spies no long start with commando, and have had their movement speed reduced, but they now gain XP from doing espionage missions, which can naturally be spent on promotions. Each turn a spy sits on a plot it reduces the cost of an espionage mission on said plot, to a limit of course.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Promotions:[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Alchemist: Bonus to poison missions[PARAGRAPH:1]Deception: Less likely to get caught[PARAGRAPH:1]Escape Artist: Less likely to die if foiled[PARAGRAPH:1]Improvise: Decrease mission cost without fortifying[PARAGRAPH:1]Instigator: Bonus to unrest missions[PARAGRAPH:1]Logistics: Bonus to sight and movement[PARAGRAPH:1]Security: Bonus to counter-espionage</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_NAVAL_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Naval Combat</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_NAVAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Naval Combat[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Naval combat was a bit bland in BTS, and so a few changes have been made to make it more interesting.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Destroyers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Destroyers were the catch all utility boat in BTS, they simply did too much. Historically destroy were the weakest of medium sized ships as far as ship to ship combat went, but they were prized for their speed and their ability to hunt submarines. In Civilization 4-Ever their bombard has been weakened, their strength lowered (except against subs), their ability to combat air has been taken away, and their cost has been reduced. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cruisers[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Cruisers are a new unit. They are able to intercept aircraft, and have a moderate bombard attack. They have the strength of the old destroyers, as well as the price, but cannot detect submarines.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Capital Ships[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Historically speaking, capital ships were in a class of their own when it comes to naval warfare, and due to their size, not many were built. The cost of battleships has been increased. The cost of carriers has also increased slightly.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Attack Submarines[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Attack Subs no longer get a bonus against other subs.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_OPTIONS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>New Game Options</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_OPTIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]New Game Options[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Tech Trading[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Tech trading is now off by default. Historically it makes little sense, and the other game options act as sort of a replacement, but this option can be used if desired.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spies Return to Nearest City[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The name says it all on this one, spies will return to your nearest city instead of your capital with this option on. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Advanced Tech Bleed[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unbenounced to the player, a technology in BTS was actually cheaper if more civilizations already had it. This system's math was coarse and bland however. This new system takes into account knowledge of civilizations with the technology, open boarder agreements, defensive pacts, alliances, vassalages, and wars. If this option is turned off the old system will be used. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Technology from Pillaging[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This option encourages players to pillage more, as well as rounding out the new economy a bit (as it provides tech without spending). With this option on each time you pillage an opponent's improvements you will be given a few beakers in a random technology that they posses that you do not. The reward for capturing a city is much larger. This option is on by default.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Improved Culture Warfare[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]After reviewing the formulas used it can be easily determined that taking over territory with culture in BTS is not really possible / doesn't work like it should. This option completely reworks the way cities generate culture. With this option on cultural warfare is much more viable. If this option is turned off the old system will be used. This option is on by default. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Non-Lethal Combat[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In BTS combat is done by taking several turns, during each one of the two sides makes an attack on the other. This option makes it so that combat ends after a certain number of rounds even if both participants are still alive. The goal here is makeing doomstack vs doomstack feel less random. now you can look at how it went after a round of combat and decide to retreat or hold out for reinforcements without taking massive casualities. To balance this healing is disabled while an enemy is adjacent, and promotions do not heal. If this option is disabled the original fight to the death mechanic is used, healing can be done next to opponents, and promotions heal. This option is on by default.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_AI_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>AI Changes</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_AI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]AI Changes[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]AI will no longer spend Espionage points on players it considers friends or insignificant.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will only use spies to harass players that it is annoyed with, at war with, or considers a threat to winning.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will not upgrade units when enemies are near by.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will build forts to capture resources outside of its borders.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI will walk great generals around with armies for the bonuses.[PARAGRAPH:2]AI identifies choke points and constructs forts on them.[PARAGRAPH:2]Implemented Better BTS AI 1.01. Summary of changes below: [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Closeness bug: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fixed AI calculations of the closeness or proximity of another empire to its borders. Previously, player A actually calculated how close enemy B's cities were to enemy B's cities, not to its own cities. This kind of subtle logic bug is difficult to track down, but can have wide ranging effects on how the AI makes decisions. The AI now appropriately calculates the proximity of enemy cities to its cities and the calculations of which enemy to attack had to be tweaked to balance the corrected numerical values returned by closeness calculations.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Retreating of sea/air units: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This new behavior was started by Solver in the unofficial patch and has been adapted and repeatedly tweaked in this mod. Basically, the AI will now move ships and air units out of threatened cities so they are less likely to be lost. Air units in lightly threatened cities now run defensive bombard missions to attack the threat, only pulling out when the city is highly threatened (some fighters will stay behind to help defend the city).[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Air defences: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In vanilla BTS once a fighter decides to air patrol in a city, it will remain air patrolling their indefinitely unless the city is attacked from the air. We have modified this behavior so that the AI is more flexible and will shift its fighters to cities which need them. This required designing a consistent rule so that fighters would stick in threatened cities and run the needed air patrol missions, as each time a fighter rebases is a lost turn of air patrol. In addition, when the AI has extra fighters it will now use them to clear out enemy defensive fighters so its bombers survive longer.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Bomber basing: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The BTS AI used bombers which happened to be nearby to support its stacks in enemy territory. Now, it also chooses where to base its bombers according to where it have land troops attacking. This is a one example of improving the coordination of actions between different pieces of the AI to make it far more potent in war.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Air combat mechanics: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]This is the one change we have made so far which really changed the mechanics of the game, not just the AI's choices. Air combat now works a bit more like land combat, making veteran air units more valuable and longer lived. This makes air combat behave more in line with the player's expectations based on the importance of experience in land combat. This change can also be disabled in GlobalDefinesAlt.xml.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Naval invasion logic: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Successfully launching naval invasions requires coordination between city production, transport and escort motion, and loading of groups of land troops. Reworking the AI's invasion system has been one of the primary pushes in this project so far. The biggest addition is the ability of the AI to reinforce its initial invasion fleet with subsequent waves, previously it basically waited to build up a brand new full invasion while its initial invasion force was whittled away. When the AI does build up enough troops to launch a second invasion (instead of just a reinforcement), it now sends the second wave near the first wave instead of often spreading out to two distinct fronts. The AI can also now time multiple invasion flotillas to show up at nearly the same time. If the AI has no land path to its enemy, it will now use the invasion production logic and load its troops into transports, previously the enemy would see at most one initial invasion wave. A related important new behavior for the AI is the ability to pickup troops which get stranded on islands or on other places around the map, something which previously could break immersion. Also, a bug where AI transports would loiter trying to pick up the units they already had onboard has been fixed, this previously could cause partially full transport flotillas to get stuck indefinitely on small islands.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Voting for peace: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The AI's voting on AP/UN resolutions for peace has been improved to better take into account how the AI is doing in war. Other new considerations for AIs that are third parties to the war are whether they want the war to continue for selfish reasons, because they share a war with one side or are about to join the war.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Privateer production bug: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fixed a bug blocking the main AI logic for producing Privateers. Previously a check for whether privateers were obsolete was made using unit class type where unit type was intended. As a consequence, the function never actually checked any naval units and always blocked the logic to produce privateers. The AI now builds Privateers but since they haven't really done it before, more work remains in making sure they get value from these units.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Attack stack tactics: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]AI attack stacks will now minimize the number of turns they spend in enemy territory or along enemy borders. This increases the surprise factor for the assault and reduces losses from counter attacks. Attack stacks with overwhelming odds will now skip bombarding and attack directly, sacrificing perhaps a couple of units for keeping the enemy from having time to reinforce the city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Vassals prepare for war: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Vassals of AI players will now begin their own preparations for war when their master does, meaning they'll have troops available both to defend themselves and contribute offensively when war breaks out. Vassals of human players will default to building more offensive units generally and you can also signal to the AI your war plans by pressing SHIFT+ALT and clicking on enemies in the scoreboard. This toggles your warplan state against enemies so you can get the same benefits during war from your vassals as the AI does. Vassals will now even be able to participate in naval invasions which require a fair amount of buildup, don't be surprised to see them send their troops to the cities you've captured on another continent and set out to make conquests of their own.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Settler bug: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]In vanilla BTS, if there were sites where the AI wanted to settle cities available on the same continent as the settler unit, the AI would never load the settler into a transport. Since AI settlers will not move through other player's territory even with open borders (fixing an annoyance from Civ3), this would stunt the AIs growth if it was cutoff from those potential city sites by another player's territory or mountains. The AI now properly loads settlers into transports if they cannot reach the target location over land.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Capitulation decisions: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Tweaks and adjustments to both sides of the capitulation decision making process, so that war mongers will sometimes annihilate enemies instead of seeming to always accept capitulation. AI will, however, still always accept capitulation when there's a danger of the enemy capitulating to someone else or of another player gaining valuable land from the mutual enemy. Fixed issue where small-size of previously capitulated civs would influence when a civ losing a war would capitulate.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Empire defense: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Added greater awareness of how wars are going for the AI. When the AI now feels it is losing, it will put an empire wide emphasis on defense and counter attackers to try to hold on.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Cottage/Workshop cycling: [\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Fixed some AI valuation bugs which led to a propensity to alternate tile improvements between cottages and workshops. These bugs would block some AI cities from getting to Towns, thus hindering the civ's tech rate. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MISC_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Misc Changes</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MISC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Miscellaneous Changes[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]Implemented BUG (Beyond the sword Unaltered Gameplay) interface mods. [PARAGRAPH:2]Astronomy now requires paper, which prolongs the time between ocean exploration and ocean colonization.[PARAGRAPH:2]Forges now allow for an additional engineer, making it easier to plant a city in barren environments or on small islands.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Colossus now only affects the city that it is built in.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Great Lighthouse now only provides one trade route per costal city.[PARAGRAPH:2]All government civics can now hurry production with gold. This is part of the economic rework.[PARAGRAPH:2]Universal Suffrage now provides +1 Culture per Specialist in addition to its other effects, because hurrying with gold is no longer unique.[PARAGRAPH:2]Cities with enemies adjacent to them cannot hurry production. This is for balance but can be justified with the fact that cities are not usually self sufficient on the inside.[PARAGRAPH:2]Walls were too good at stopping early game aggression, and castles were lackluster, and so their resistances to bombardment have been swapped.[PARAGRAPH:2]Upgrading units now removes half of the unit's current hit points. This change is partially to balance out the gold decrease of upgrades, and partially to prevent armies from instantly becoming better when a new technology is reached. It's also logically justifiable as troops must be trained with the new equipment.[PARAGRAPH:2]Aircraft now gain minimal experience points from doing bombing missions. Bombers had no way good way of gaining XP before this. [PARAGRAPH:2]Slavery's cost to hurry production has been reworked.[PARAGRAPH:2]Culture output of Wonders has been halved. Industrial was too strong at cutlure pushing. This change was also made for the Improved Culture Warfare, and if you play with that option off you won't even notice this culture missing. [PARAGRAPH:2]Unbenounced to the player, advancing through the eras actually applies a penalty to your research and your economy in general. This penalty was linear in BTS. I have doubled the penalty for entering the medieval era and removed the penalty for entering the Renaissance. This change is both historically logical, and encourages more medieval wars, as the era is slightly longer.[PARAGRAPH:2]Espionage can now be built from cities, just like wealth, once computers have been researched.[PARAGRAPH:2]Removed the feature where building's double their culture output after '1000' turns (it was like 22 turns for some reason)[PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced Great Artist culture production to 8 from 12 and Great Work culture to 1200 from 4000[PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced SDI's chance to intercept nukes to 50% from 75% (nukes were really bad past lasers and for something that takes so many hamemrs to build it should never be that bad)[PARAGRAPH:2]Sistine Chapel Culture per specialist reduced to 1 from 2 and cupture per religious building reduced to 3 from 5. [PARAGRAPH:2]Took one scientist away from the library and gave it to the university. [PARAGRAPH:2]Roads/Railroads can now be destroyed with aircraft if there are no improvments on their tile. [PARAGRAPH:2]Reduced culture per resource of all corperations. [PARAGRAPH:2]Implemented Hi-Res Blue Marble Textures. [PARAGRAPH:2]UI now shows commerce gain for cutting down forests and jungles next to rivers. </English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MAPS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>New Map Generators</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_MAPS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]New Map Generators[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]NewWorld[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A mix of Big and Small, Terra, and Hemispheres. This map script generates a mash up of large and small islands, with some large ones uninhabited. Bodies of water will be smaller, and combat will be tighter.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Planet_Generator_0_68[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Creates a wide variety of planets based on extensive customizable sliders.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]PerfectWorld2[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]The most famous map script, this script generates an earth like planet based on things like climate zones, plate tectonics, and ancient meteoric impacts. Has an option to keep one continent uninhabited. Unlike other civ 4 maps scripts climate regions will be very pronounced in this world.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Totestra[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A fork of pw2, this map script is just perfect world 2 but with several of the internal variables exposed for tweaking.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]PerfectMongoose_v320[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]A backword port of Perfect World 3 from civ 5, this is supposedly more refined version of perfect world 2</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_CREDITS_TEXT</Tag>
		<English>Thanks</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_FE_CREDITS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Thanks[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]All mods and mod components included with implicit permission (due to age of community) and expicit thanks[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]TheLopez[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Air Combat Experience v0.3BtS[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]killmeplease[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Commanders v.1.0 beta fix 1[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]NeseryozniyVET[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Dynamic Civics Screen[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]deanej[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Convert Production to Espionage[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Lemon Merchant[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Lemon's Spy Mod[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Red Key[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Super Forts[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Trojan Sheep[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Super Spies[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]akerum68 &amp; fellow contributors[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]BUG Mod[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]jdog5000[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Better BTS AI[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]jdog5000 &amp; civfanatics community[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Unofficial Patch for 3.19</English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
